sweetpeasandsaffron.com 2019-04-26

# Privacy Policy & Terms Of Use | Sweet Peas and Saffron

Sweet Peas and Saffron found at https://sweetpeasandsaffron.com/ (“Site”) is governed by the following privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”).

We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting it. The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you what personally identifiable information we may collect and how it may be used.

By visiting or interacting with our Site, you agree to be bound by the terms of this Privacy Policy. We may change this Privacy Policy at any time, and your continued use of our Site indicates your agreement to the revised terms. Accordingly, you should review this Privacy Policy from time to time to keep informed of such amendments. The most recent date of revision will be indicated prominently at the top of the Privacy Policy.

Please also make sure to read our Terms of Use, Nutrition Disclaimer, Comment Policy and Photo/Recipe Sharing Policy as it supplements and forms part of this Privacy Policy. By using the Site you are agreeing to be bound by the terms of this Privacy Policy, the Terms of Use, Nutritional Disclaimer, Comment Policy and Photo/Recipe Sharing Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this policy or any revised Privacy Policy, please do not further interact with the Site.

**WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT AND HOW IS IT USED?**

Information You Voluntarily Submit to the Site: We may collect personal information from you such as your name or email address. We only collect Personal Information where you voluntarily provide it. For example, you may voluntarily submit information to the Site by leaving a comment, subscribing to a newsletter, or submitting a contact form.

Information We Collect from Others: We may receive information about you from other sources.

Automatically-Collected Information: We automatically collect certain information about you and the device with which you access the Site. For example, when you use the Site, we will log your IP address, operating system type, browser type, referring website, pages you viewed, and the dates/times when you accessed the Site. We may also collect information about actions you take when using the Site, such as links clicked.

Cookies: We may log information using cookies, which are small data files stored on your browser by the Site. We may use both session cookies, which expire when you close your browser, and persistent cookies, which stay on your browser until deleted, to provide you with a more personalized experience on the Site.

**HOW YOUR INFORMATION MAY BE USED**

We may use the information collected in the following ways:

To operate and maintain the Site;

To send you promotional information, such as newsletters. Each email promotion will provide information on how to opt-out of future mailings;

To send you administrative communications, such as administrative emails, confirmation emails, technical notices, updates on policies, or security alerts;

To respond to your comments or inquiries;

To provide you with user support;

To track and measure advertising on the Site;

To protect, investigate, and deter against unauthorized or illegal activity.

**THIRD-PARTY USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

We may share your personal information with third parties when you explicitly authorize us to share your information.

Additionally, the Site may use third-party service providers to service various aspects of the Site. Each third-party service provider’s use of your personal information is dictated by their respective privacy policies.

The Site currently uses the following third-party service providers:

Google Analytics – this service tracks Site usage and provides information such as referring websites and user actions on the Site. Google Analytics may capture your IP address, but no other personal information is captured by Google Analytics.

ConvertKit – this service is used for delivery of email updates and newsletters. We store your name and email address for purposes of delivering such communications. Please refer to ConvertKit’s privacy policy for further information.

PushEngage – this service is used to send you push notifications through your web browser, should you choose. Please refer to PushEngage’s privacy policy for further information.

At this time, your personal information is not shared with any other third-party applications. This list may be amended from time to time in the Site’s sole discretion.

Except when required by law or as set out in this policy, we will not sell, distribute, or reveal your email addresses or other personal information without your consent; however, we may disclose or transfer personal information collected through the Site to third parties who acquire all or a portion of our business, which may be the result of a merger, consolidation, or purchase of all or a portion of our assets, or in connection with any bankruptcy or reorganization proceeding brought by or against us.

**ANONYMOUS DATA**

From time to time, we may use anonymous data, which does not identify you alone, or when combined with data from other parties. This type of anonymous data may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. Examples of this anonymous data may include analytics or information collected from cookies.

**PUBLICLY VISIBLE INFORMATION**

If you create a user profile on the Site or leave a comment, certain information may be publicly visible. Your email address will never be available publicly. At your option, you may also add a link to your website.

Users may see your username, avatar, profile description and website information.

**COOKIES**

The Site uses cookies to store visitors’ preferences, record user-specific information on what pages users access or visit, ensure that visitors are not repeatedly sent the same banner ads, customize Site content based on visitors’ browser type or other information that the visitor sends. Cookies may also be used by third-party services, such as Google Analytics, as described herein.

Users may, at any time, prevent the setting of cookies, by the Site, by using a corresponding setting of your internet browser and may thus permanently deny the setting of cookies. Furthermore, already set cookies may be deleted at any time via an Internet browser or other software programs. This is possible in all popular Internet browsers. However, if users deactivate the setting of cookies in your Internet browser, not all functions of our Site may be entirely usable.

**ADVERTISING**

Display Ads

We may use third-party advertising companies to serve content and advertisements when you visit the Site, which may use cookies, as noted above.

Retargeting Ads

From time to time, the Site may engage in remarketing efforts with third-party companies, such as Google, Facebook, or Instagram, in order to market the Site. These companies use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visits to the Site.

Affiliate Program Participation

The Site may engage in affiliate marketing, which is done by embedding tracking links into the Site. If you click on a link for an affiliate partnership, a cookie will be placed on your browser to track any sales for purposes of commissions.

Sweet Peas and Saffron is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and links to Amazon.com. As part of this Amazon Associates program, the Site will post customized links, provided by Amazon, to track the referrals to their website. This program utilizes cookies to track visits for the purposes of assigning commission on these sales.

Newsletters

On the Site, you may subscribe to our newsletter, which may be used for advertising purposes. All newsletters sent may contain tracking pixels. The pixel is embedded in emails and allows an analysis of the success of online marketing campaigns. Because of these tracking pixels, we may see if and when you open an email and which links within the email you click. Also, this allows the Site to adapt the content of future newsletters to the interests of the user. This behavior will not be passed on to third parties.

**RIGHTS RELATED TO YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

Opt-out – You may opt-out of future email communications by following the unsubscribe links in our emails. You may also notify us at sweetpeasandsaffron@gmail.com to be removed from our mailing list.

Access – You may access the personal information we have about you by submitting a request to sweetpeasandsaffron@gmail.com.

Amend – You may contact us at sweetpeasandsaffron@gmail.com to amend or update your personal information.

Forget – In certain situations, you may request that we erase or forget your personal data. To do so, please submit a request to sweetpeasandsaffron@gmail.com.

Please note that we may need to retain certain information for record keeping purposes or to complete transactions, or when required by law.

**SENSITIVE PERSONAL INFORMATION**

At no time should you submit sensitive personal information to the Site. This includes your social security number, information regarding race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious beliefs, health information, criminal background, or trade union memberships. If you elect to submit such information to us, it will be subject to this Privacy Policy.

**CHILDREN’S INFORMATION**

The Site does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 16. If a parent or guardian believes that the Site has personally identifiable information of a child under the age of 16 in its database, please contact us immediately at sweetpeasandsaffron@gmail.com and we will use our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.

**CONTACT INFORMATION**

At any time, please contact us at sweetpeasandsaffron@gmail.com for questions related to this Privacy Policy.

Last updated: January 28, 2019.

Acceptance of Terms Through Use

By using Sweet Peas and Saffron Ltd.’s (“Sweet Peas and Saffron”, “we” or “us”) website (the “Site”), you agree to be bound by all terms, conditions and notices contained or referenced herein (the “Terms of Use”) and the Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”). Sweet Peas and Saffron reserves the right to change or discontinue any feature of the Site, including, but not limited to, the Terms of Use, at any time, by posting revisions on the Site. You agree to be deemed apprised and bound by any changes to these Terms and Conditions and your continued use of the Site indicates your agreement to the revised terms. You also agree to review this information from time to time as may be required to keep informed of any revisions to the Terms and Conditions. If you do not agree to the terms of this or any revised policy, please exit the Site immediately.

Links to Third Party Sites & Services

The site contains links to and from sites operated by third parties. Sweet Peas and Saffron makes no representations whatsoever about any third party content that you may access from the Site, or about any website from which you may access the Site and/or which may be linked to this Site. We provide third party content and links only as a courtesy to our users, and such links / content do not imply our endorsement of any linked site / content. The linked sites / content are not under our influence or control, and we are not responsible for any third party content or the contents of any linked site or subsequent links from that site. Our Privacy Policy is only applicable when you are on this Site. Please review the streaming providers’ and the linked sites’ use agreements and privacy policies, and if you do not agree to be bound by the terms, we recommend that you terminate your use of that service or your visit to the site.

Intellectual Property

You acknowledge that all content and materials available on this Site, including the selection, co-ordination, arrangement and enhancement of such content, as well as content original to it, are protected by national and international copyrights, trademarks, service marks, patents, patent registration rights, trade secrets, know-how or other proprietary rights and laws and are owned by us or our licensors or we have obtained the necessary permission of the owner of the intellectual property in such content to use the content on our Site.

Lawful Use

You agree to use the Site or its contents for lawful purposes and only as expressly permitted in this Terms of Use and for no other purpose. Except where otherwise noted, you may download, print or view individual pages for non-commercial use only, provided you do not delete or change any of the information, including copyright or trademark notices. Except as otherwise permitted herein and as we may expressly authorize, you agree not to sell, license, rent, modify, distribute, copy, reproduce, transmit, publicly display, publicly perform, publish, adapt, edit or create derivative works from the content or materials on the Site or otherwise in any way exploit any of the content of the Site, in whole or in part or violate or infringe in any way upon the rights of others, or do or cause to be done anything which is unlawful, threatening, abusive, defamatory, invasive of privacy or publicity rights, vulgar, obscene, profane or otherwise objectionable, or that which encourages conduct that would constitute a criminal offence, gives rise to civil liability or otherwise violate any law, or which, without our express prior approval, contains advertising or any solicitation with respect to products or services. Any conduct by you that in our discretion restricts or inhibits any other user from using or enjoying the Site will not be permitted.

Disclaimer of Warranties

You expressly agree that all material and information provided through this site (“Content”) is provided on “as is” and “as available” basis and that there is no representation or warranty, express or implied on the part of Sweet Peas and Saffron in respect of such Content.

Limitation of Liability

Under no circumstances shall Sweet Peas and Saffron, its employees, officers, directors, shareholders, agents, consultants and licensees be liable for any damages, whether legal, equitable or otherwise arising from the use or inability to use any Content on this site.

Indemnification

You agree to defend, indemnify, and hold Sweet Peas and Saffron including its employees, officers, directors, shareholders, agents, consultants and licensees harmless from and against any and all liabilities, claims and expenses, including attorney’s fees, that arise from your use or misuse of the Site or the Content therein, including without limitation your violation of the Terms of Use herein. We reserve the right, at our own expense, to assume the exclusive defence and control of any matter otherwise subject to indemnification by you, in which event you will co-operate with us in asserting any available defences.

International Use

By choosing to access the Site from any location other than Canada, you accept full responsibility for compliance with all local laws that are applicable. Sweet Peas and Saffron makes no representation that materials on the Site are appropriate or available for use in locations outside Canada, and accessing them from territories where their contents are illegal is prohibited.

Security Precautions

The services and information provided are protected using industry standard security precautions. It is up to you to fully understand the risks and threats of using the public Internet, and to be sufficiently aware of those risks to adequately protect your confidential information. Sweet Peas and Saffron provides information regarding security and privacy in our Privacy Policy. This document is provided as a guideline only, and it is up to the user to remain current and exercise care when using the Internet. You should seek professional advice on protecting your privacy and evaluating the security of the information systems you are using.

Choice of Law

This Agreement shall be construed in accordance with the laws of the Province of Alberta, and the Federal laws of Canada applicable therein, without regard to its conflict of laws rules. You expressly agree that any claim or action arising out of or relating to these Terms of Use or your use of the Site shall be filed only in the courts of the Province of Alberta or the Federal Court of Canada, if applicable, and you further agree and submit to the exercise of personal jurisdiction of such courts for the purpose of litigating any such claim or action.

Integration and Severability

This Terms of Use and our Privacy Policy constitute the entire agreement between Sweet Peas and Saffron and you with respect to the Site and supersedes all prior or contemporaneous communications and proposals between us with respect to the Site. If any provision of this Terms of Use agreement is determined to be invalid or unenforceable, all other provisions shall remain in full force and effect. The section headings used herein are for convenience only and shall not be given any legal import.

Unauthorized Use and Termination

You agree to use the Site only for authorized and legal activities. Sweet Peas and Saffron reserves the right, in our sole discretion, to terminate your access to all or part of the Site, with or without notice and for any reason whatsoever.

Privacy and Disclosure

You have read and accept the terms of our Privacy Policy.
